NYSUT Field Services Department Files. 6174/004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Coordinator's Meeting (1 of 2), 1979 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  May 15-16, 1979. Meeting agenda; summary of meeting, by Diane Wagner; list of articles for discussion; report by Division of Research and Educational Services; letter from Martin E. Segal Company evaluating merits of self-insurance proposal for Tompkins Seneca Tioga BOCES; Daily Star newspaper clipping, "Lawyer bills school district for time talking to reporter" following lawyer's dismissal from teachers' union negotiations; New York Times clipping, "Removing Incompetent Teachers Is Growing Problem for Schools"; other clippings; draft NYSUT report, "A Joint Employee OrganizationsDistrict Approach to Alcoholism Recovery Programs"
- Coordinator's Meeting (2 of 2), 1979 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  May 15-16, 1979. Meeting agenda, with items added in pencil; handwritten notes; articles for discussion; NYEA materials; pie chart showing expenditures by VOTE/COPE on 1978 state and federal elections; newspaper clippings and article reprints; Public Employee Conference Bills as at 1/23/79; brochures, "AFL-CIO Manual for Shop Stewards" and UUP "To Keep Pace with a Changing World"; summary of actions of NYSUT Board of Directors meeting, January 26-27, 1979
- Coordinator's Reports, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  Febtruary, 1979. Reports from John O'Leary, Nassau, re negotiations, layoffs, Levittown United Teachers fines of $170,000, field rep visibility; report from Robert J. Allen, North Country, re negotiations at several locals, arbitrations, tenure hearings, improper practice charges; report from Chuck Rogers, Southern Tier Regional Office (STRO), re Ithaca College Faculty Association certification by NLRB, problem with Horseheads Teachers Association; report on UUP by Evelyn Hartman, executive director; report by Vinnie Grove, Utica, re impasses, student discipline conference, legislative breakfast, retirement seminars; report by Leon Lieberman, Albany, re negotiations, organizing at several districts; report by Ray Samson, Rochester, re organizing at Seneca Falls, Avon, Rochester Institute of Technology, Community College of the Finger Lakes, Monroe County BOCES II Teacher Aides, Rochester Regional Organizing Council, Wheatland-Chili Non-Teaching Association, and Hilton School Employees Association, NYEA activities in various districts; confidential memos to Jim Conti from Ron Uba, Western NY, re home visits in the Jamestown election, largely negative reception, Wellsville election; report from John DeGregorio, Suffolk, re negotiations, public relations; report from Tony Ficcio, NYC, re NYU, Catholic schools, missed organizing potential at Columbia for lack of staff; report from Stanley Kern, Mid-Hudson, re settlements, impasses, other negotiations, organizing potential SRP group in Saugerties; report from Frank Squillace, Syracuse, re organizing, noting 53 bargaining units in central NY area
- Coordinator's Meeting, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  February 14, 1979. Meeting agenda; outline of executive director's report; summary of meeting, by Diane Wagner; list of articles for discussion; letter to coordinators from Jim Conti re unemployment insurance; proposal for discussion at coordinator's meeting, re teacher-to-teacher conferences; Project Teach update; memo from Herb Magidson, secretary-treasurer, re agency fees; report by Division of Research and Educational Services; NYSUT Information Bulletin re recommendations in the 1979-80 state Executive Budget for SUNY community colleges; January 19, 1979 (vol.1, no. 1) Healthwire newsletter by Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals; paper, "A Teacher Union's View of Public Sector Negotiations (What Should be the Parents and Lay Community's Role in the Process)"; newspaper clippings and article reprints
- Coordinator's Reports, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  January, 1979. Report from Tony Ficcio, NYC, re NYU, suggesting update go to Al Shanker; reports from Ficcio re his efforts in organizing NYU, assault on his professional integrity; report from Frank Squillace, Syracuse, re organizing or school-related personnel in Solvey, bus drivers in Cazenovia, negotiations, workshops; report from Robert G. Klein, Elmsford, re negotiations, organizing; report from John O'Leary, Nassau, re organizing at Hicksville, Plainview, C.W. Post, and Sewanhaka, negotiations of 19 teacher contracts, 6 non-teaching, trouble at Nassau Community College; UUP status report by Evelyn Hartman; report from Charles Rodgers, Southern Tier, re Ithaca College election, pending NLRB certification, organizing attempts at Corning Hospital, school districts, with attached newsletter; report from Ron Uba, Western NY, re organizing efforts in Jamestown, Buffalo, and Wellsville; report from Robert J. Allen, North Country, re slow negotiations, weak NYEA activity, outcome of arbitrations, political action and legislative workshops; report from Vincent Grove, Utica, re impasses, pending negotiations, potential strikes, increase in membership by 73; report from Stanley Kern, Mid-Hudson, re settlement by Liberty school-related personnel; report from Ray Samson, Rochester, re locals at impasse, NYEA activity, bargaining crisis at Avon school district; report by John DeGregorio, Suffolk, re NYEA activity at Stony Brook, Islip, Deer Park/Levittown, negotiations at Harborfields, successful workshop; report from Leon Lieberman, Albany, re negotiations, organizing, NYEA locals, need for more field staff
- Vito De Leonardis Coordinator's Meeting, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  January 17, 1979. Meeting agenda, 9-page summary of meeting, by Diane Wagner; list of articles for discussion; report by Division of Research and Educational Services; Revised Wage and Price Standards, Council on Wage and Price Stability, December 13, 1978; Federal Register report by Council on Wage and Price Stability: Noninflationary Pay and Price Behavior Voluntary Standards, Part V, December 28, 1978; Voluntary Pay and Price Standards: Interim Final Rules; Request for Comments, January 4, 1979; NYSUT Management Memo; article reprints
- Accounting, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  Memo re changes to NYSUT expense reimbursement policy; memo re proposed dues recommendation for 1991-92 and 1992-93, with attached income and expense projection and related materials; memo re health care cost containment; memo re financial situation and outlook; memo from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson re proposed budget cuts announced by Gov. Mario Cuomo, with attached list of impact of cuts by district; memo re 1990-91 dues structure; memo from Jim Conti with attached Labor Organization Annual Report form to be filed with U.S. Department of Labor; memo re dues revision implementation; memo to local presidents, "Important Agency Fee Advance Reduction Information"; re wellness program proposed by American Institute for Preventative Medicine; memo re health and safety training; memo re hazard communications program, with attached proposal by United University Professions Staff Office; NYSUT financial statements as of January 31, 1990
- Legal Albany H.Q., 1990 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  Memo from New York State School Boards Association re legislative proposals re changes to 3020a disciplinary hearing procedures, with attached survey for school superintendents; memo from NYSUT counsel Bernard Ashe to Jim Conti re Kidwell v. TCIU, requiring unions to accommodate members' objections to use of money for political purposes, December 20; memo from Ashe re obligation to bargain about decisions to subcontract academic programs to a BOCES, with attached copy of decision (Webster Central School District et al. v. PERB et al.), May 15; memo re re-opening of unemployment insurance cases, May 15; memo from Jim Conti to regional staff directors re decision; memo from Ashe re legality of mandatory retirement policy, June 14; memo from Jim Conti re drug-free workplace requirements, May 2; memos from Jim Conti to Bernard Ashe and regional staff directors re PERB administrative law judge decision in Watkins Glen Faculty Association v. Watkins Glen Central School District, implications for negotiating E.I.T. funds, March 27; memos re appeal of Maureen Keesler, with decision by state Commissioner of Education dismissing the appeal, March; letter from New York State School Boards Association, soliciting school attorneys to use the NYSSBA legal services for a fee, December 18, 1989
- Legal NYC, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  Memo from Jim Conti to NYSUT legal counsel James Sandner re early retirement incentives, with attached Older Workers Benefit Protection Act text and analysis, Bureau of National Affairs Labor Relations Reporter, October 15, 1990; memo to NYSUT officers and staff from counsel James Sandner re decision in NY Court of Appeals in Sobol and NYSUT advs. Schneider re Excellence in Teaching eligibility, with attached decision, June 28; memo form Jim Conti to NYSUT counsel James Sandner suggesting that he make a presentation to the Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Conference re nurses' professional responsibilities and liabilities, September 5; memo from Sandner re Jose P. v. Board of Education, City School District, City of New York, assignment of counsel, August 8; memo from Jim Conti re agency fees and union shops at Nassau, Suffolk, and Elmsford school districts, July 12
- Legislation, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  Memo from Department of Civil Service Division of Employee Benefits re option transfer period, outlining health insurance plan options, pre-tax contribution program, October 22; cover memo re questionnaire to local presidents, November 21; New York State School Boards Association Legislative Bulletin: Questions and Answers on the Teachers' Retirement System, May 30; memos to local presidents from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson re Gov. Mario Cuomo's proposed state aid reductions, with attached spreadsheet of impacts by district, November-December; Cuomo's Message to the Legislature ("State of the State"), excerpt on education, reprinted by NYSUT, January 3; memo re duty of fair representation legislation, with attached text of bill in Assembly, August 17; preliminary report on indoor air quality, prepared for the Senate Democratic Task Force on Indoor Air Quality, September 1990, with cover memo to Jim Conti from John Costello, NYSUT Legislative Department; memo re mandatory class size bill, November 28; memo to local presidents re update of 1990 legislative report, August 10; memos re approach to proposal in Congress to amend the National Labor Relations Act to speed up certification process, May-July; memo re Assembly proposal to amend the Public Health Law to provide information to health care workers on their exposure to the AIDS virus, question of whether NYSUT should support or oppose, June 28, with attached text of legislation; memo from Jim Conti re pending health care legislation that would ban Medicaid reimbursement to health care facilities that used tax money to fight union organizing activity, June 21; lobbying materials, including "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity," "An Overview: Pension Reform: The Need Is Compelling," letters to legislators; text of bill in Assembly re asbestos removal, March 28, 1989; memos re Executive Order No. 131, insuring that the state's administrative hearing system operated in an impartial and timely way; New Jersey Department of Health Proposed Standards for Indoor Air Quality, with cover memo from Jim Conti suggesting that the information might be helpful in considering a draft proposal for New York, January 22; draft proposal for indoor air pollution legislation, by the New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health (NYCOSH), with cover memo from Jim Conti, December 19; memo asking whether school districts had reduced health insurance benefits for retirees, January 19
- New York Teacher (Newspaper), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  Series of articles from NYSUT official publication, New York Teacher, re state retirement system; printing schedule, list of major stories for each issue, list of columns, potential new columns, potential focus areas for following year; A Study of the UFT Bulletin and New York Teacher, conducted by Clark, Martire & Bartolomeo, Inc.; draft of article on Commissioner's ruling on asbestos in schools, with note that Jim Conti recommended against doing story
- President's Office, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  Memos from president Tom Hobart to staff re NYSUT smoking policy in the workplace, March 28 and July 19; program for testimonial luncheon and Four Freedoms Award by Italian American Labor Council, honoring Tom Hobart, December 8; letter from the New York State School Boards Association, New York State Council of School Superintendents, and Association of School Business Officials to Gov. Mario Cuomo, urging elimination of Excellence In Teaching funds and other items, with cover memo to Tom Hobart from Jim Conti, December 1; art materials safety alert from Consumer Products Safety Commission, with cover memo from Tom Hobart to local presidents, September 4; memo from Jim Conti re NYSUT Task Force on Health and Safety, with attached list of members; ad by NEA in Education Week, with cover memo from Jim Conti, January 24; clipping from NEA Today, with cover memo from Jim Conti noting that national had to "bail out" NEA-NY, January 24; memo from Tom Hobart re new smoking regulations following new state law, December 20; NYSUT 1990 Annual Report and daily summaries of proceedings of the Representative Assembly, with cover letter from Tom Hobart to NYSUT staff, April 2
- Public Relations, 1990 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  Memo from Jim Conti to NYSUT public relations director Peter Boespflug re Jobs with Justice Health Care Action Day, noting reluctance to get involved until differences with AFSCME were resolved, December 18; materials re event; memos re brochures on pesticides, Right-to-Know, indoor air pollution, AFT publication reprints. Includes two photographs
- Research (Division of Research and Educational Services), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  Memo re Regents appointments to the State Board for Nursing, December 13; materials re new teacher evaluation policy jointly developed by the Syracuse Teachers Association and the school district, April; NYSUT Information Bulletin re education reform survey, April 1990
- Educational Services (Division of Research and Educational Services), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  Letter to Tom Hobart from Target Consultants International Ltd., providers of violence-suppression training, with cover letter to Jim Conti for discussion by Health and Safety Committee, January 3; weekly reports from Chuck Santelli re school budget defeats; memo re mentor-teacher internship programs, March 18; memo re State Education Department's removal of Watertown school district from Excellence and Accountability Program because of missed deadline, with attached newspaper clippings; memo re problems with implementation of D.A.R.E. program in Rome school district, January 8; local leader's survey on educational reform, February 16; results of survey, June 12; memo to NYSUT Executive Committee re revised NYSUT policy on selection procedures for the Board of Regents; NYSUT monthly report prepared by Division of Research and Educational Services, re EIT median salaries for 1990-91, other issues
- Reimbursable Cost Manual (Handicapped Children), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  "Reimbursable Cost Manual for Programs Receiving Funding under Article 81 and Article 89 of Education Law to Educate Children with Handicapping Conditions," July 1989 and August 1990 editions, with cover letter to regional staff directors, October 24, 1990
- Member Benefits (Payroll Deductions), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  Memo urging members to use payroll deduction for their dues; related correspondence
- Jim Conti Correspondence (Field Services), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  October - December, 1990. Memos authorizing filing of Improper Practice charges at several districts; chain letter addressed to several union leaders in support of ending apartheid in South Africa, initiated by a professor at the University of South Africa, with list of circulation to date, November 20; request to Bill Keleher for any and all health and safety language in collective bargaining agreements, December 20; request to NYSUT counsel Bernard Ashe for opinion re Kidwell v. TCIU case, December 20; memo to NYSUT public relations director Peter Boespflug re Jobs with Justice Health Care Action Day, noting reluctance to get involved until differences with AFSCME were resolved, December 18; requests for reports on membership promotion campaigns for various locals, December 18; memo to Ray Sampson complimenting him for excellent research on what constitutes a strike, December 18; letters to several local presidents, urging them to reconsider receiving health and safety training, as it would affect the amount of a grant received by NYSUT, December 17; memo to file re meeting with Public Employment Relations Board re impact of state fiscal crisis on agency, legislation requiring it to become revenue-producing, December 17; BOCES Steering Committee meeting notice, December 14; inquiry to Chuck Santelli re WEC Student Teaching proposal, noting that coalition appeared to be dominated by management interests, December 14; request to NYSUT counsel Jim Sandner for analysis of the Older Workers Benefit Protection Act on Early Retirement incentive clauses, December 14; letter to state Department of Labor Hazard Abatement Board, nominating the New York Coalition for Alternatives to Pesticides for a training grant, December 14; cover letters to notices of safety and health violations sent to school districts, December 3 and October 29; notice of OSHA training session, November 29; letters to regional staff directors notifying them of nomination to Blue Cross/Blue Shield Regional Advisory Council, November 28; memo to OSHA reps that NYSUT would conduct analysis of the AHERA Management Plans under a grant from the NYS Department of Labor, requesting copy of plan from each area, November 26; letter to NYSUT counsel Bernard Ashe re health and safety liability issues for science teachers, requesting meeting, November 21; memos to regional staff directors re health and safety training and assistance, November 16 and 8; letter to Roger Wheeler, whose daughter might have been entitled to additional pay at R-C-G BOCES, November 16; letter notifying Doreen Ellis, UFT, that she had been appointed to NYSUT Task Force on Safety and Health by Board of Directors, November 16; memo to regional staff directors requesting bargaining load of each labor relations specialist in their office, November 8; notice of sexual harassment training session, November 8; letter to director of field services of AFT, requesting assistance for Wappingers Federation of Transit Custodial and Maintenance Workers in resolving internal problems, November 8; letter to regional staff directors re membership promotion, targeted to a list of locals, with attached description of AFT Full Membership Program, October 24; memo to regional staff directors re right of State Education Department Division of Civil Rights and Intercultural Relations to review contracts for possible discriminatory clauses based on race, sex, age, and disabilities, October 22; memo requesting a copy of testimony at Assemblyman Richard Gottfried's hearing on indoor air pollution, October 19; memo directing that the Onondaga-Cortland-Madison BOCES local inform the Department of Labor that the district was not complying with the requirement that Right-to-Know training be provided, October 17; memo re new test for commercial drivers, October 11-12; letter to president of Roscoe Teachers Association re changes in staff assignments at NYSUT Mid-Hudson Regional Office, October 12; memo describing the Civil Service Participating Agencies Advisory Council, October 9; cover letters to various documents, not attached
- Jim Conti Correspondence (1 of 2), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  April 2 - September 28, 1990. Memos authorizing filing of Improper Practice charges at several districts; report from Jim Conti to regional staff directors on commercial driver's license conference, requirement to pass a new test, noting that many school bus drivers were functionally illiterate, dispute over who would fund training, June 27; letters re self-insurance, June 28; letters re meeting with interns, June 25; inquiry re stop-loss insurance, June 21; request for information re number of school districts and individuals in Orange-Ulster BOCES insurance plan, related questions, June 21; cover letters re safety and health violations at various school districts; memo re meeting to discuss Department of Labor training program for "win-win bargaining," June 12; memo re subcontracting to BOCES after Webster decision, June 8; memos to National Committee on Pay Equity, AFT director of information services, soliciting opinions re videotape on pay equity, June 7; memo to regional staff directors re videotape, June 4; Testimony of James Conti, Director of Field Services, NYSUT, before the New York State Assembly Public Hearing of the Standing Committee on Education, re school building safety, June 5, 1990, with cover letter to Leon Lieberman; confidential memo re vacation accrual formula in OCAW-NYCOSH contract, May 23; memo re substance abuse policy endorsed by the NYS School Boards Association, noting that it was one of the better ones, did not compel drug testing without reasonable suspicion, May 23; memo re sexual harassment prevention training, May 22; memo re flexible spending accounts, noting that they did not apply to retirees since they were no longer considered employees, May 22; letter to member Jill Lerner re concern that Livingston Manor Faculty Association handled her complaint appropriately, May 22; invitation to AFT assistant director for safety and health to attend conference, "Safety and Health in the 90s," cosponsored by NYS AFL-CIO, NYCOSH, and others, May 11; memo re East Moriches smoking policy, question of filing an Improper Practice charge for unilaterally changing terms of employment, May 9; memos calling a meeting for labor relations specialists who service Special Act schools, May 8; letter to deputy chief of training, NYS Emergency Management Office, requesting information re Emergency Preparedness Program, May 8; letter to AFT, requesting copy of Asbestos: A Time Bomb in Our Schools, May 2; memo re introductory text of pesticide brochures from the Department of Environmental Conservation, May 2; memo re decision that school districts can randomly drug-test school bus drivers, April 25; document, "Health and Safety Provisions Found in Some NYSUT Contracts," with cover letter to AFT assistant director of health and safety, April 24; request to regional staff directors for information re health and safety training conducted by field representatives since September 1989, needed for grant application to NYS Department of Labor, April 23; memos re arbitration and brief-writing seminars, April 23; memo re potential investigation by AFT of situation at Highland Teachers Association, April 19; letters to individuals hired to work as interns at NYSUT, April 6; memos re health care conference, universal health care proposal for New York, April 5; cover letters to various documents, not attached
- Jim Conti Correspondence (2 of 2), 1990 (Box 37, Folder 28)